There's a dark truth to creating content
on social media, and it's that you are
going to have to rob people at some point.
You're going to have to steal their ideas,
their hooks, their metaphors, even their
props. It took me a while to realize this,
but sometimes a good theft is
exactly what your business
and brand needs.
Let's remove it from content as an example
for a second.
The best Brazilian jujitsu athlete of all
time is Gordon Ryan, and Gordon Ryan's
coach is John Danaher. Gordon
is only Gordon because of John.
It's no coincidence
that the best grappler in the world had
the best coach in the
world. And then John Danaher's coach
was Renzo Gracie, again, one of the best
coaches in the world.
They call this standing on the shoulders
of giants.
But really what it means
is ripping off the shit from the person
above me.
Case in point, Ed Lawrence. Now,
the reason I give Ed so much love
is I've been copying his shit,
and I'm not afraid to say it.
But there's a difference. I hired Ed,
I paid Ed.
Ed taught me this, and he didn't say,
"Rip me off or rip other people off." The
actual skill he taught me
is to appreciate and assess what
is working
for other channels, for other niches,
because that's really what we do.
You see, we're not financial traders.
We don't sell and share stocks.
Our world is social media.
And if we can zoom out for a second
and realize we are day traders of people's
attention on social media, and we
are looking for certain topics
and trends to jump
on and make content of to add value to,
we can do better on social media.
So you are an idiot
if you see something that's working
and you don't try and copy
it yourself. That Ashton Hall,
the guy that went viral for being
a twat.
Everyone jumps onto it because they know
it's a trend, whether MrBeast,
Logan Paul, whoever it is.
And what we must do
is look at things within our own
niche and also niches outside of it
and see what's working.
Now, not how to do it was
that Scott lad who copied the transcript
word for
word. Don't copy people word for word.
But you can take a title
or a thumbnail and make your own version
of it.
Even look in Hollywood. Said before,
Batman's been done loads of times.
Spider-Man's been done loads of times.
Funny enough, I learned that from Ed.
It is the twist that we put onto
that content.
This week, a lad
that I've had in my mentorship grew 60,000
followers from
a single reel. And what
was his reel about?
Aspartame in Coke Zero.
He copied most of
that from me because I told him to.
I copied most of
that from a creator called Steve Kraft.
Steve Kraft and all three of us all took
our information in that reel from a guy
called Menno Henselmans.
But here's the amazing thing.
The reason that all of us went viral with
our videos was there was an audience of
people that still didn't know that.
It's easy for us to go, "Oh,
everyone knows that."
But they obviously don't or it
wouldn't have gone viral.
People would've got bored.
And even for some of us into the world of
content creation, we could've been
creating content for years,
and then you see that one comment
that goes, "Wow, it
finally makes sense." There
is an element of having to copy
things.
The first electric car company would've
come out.
Even Tesla share all their patents online
so other companies can copy
Tesla because that's good for their
mission of getting everyone electric.
TV shows, when "Big Brother" came out,
then suddenly "Love Island" came out.
These are all emulations
and copies of different variations.
Even in the technology space. Apple
were the first to make the iPhone without
any
buttons. BlackBerry didn't keep up.
Then Android, Samsung,
all of these companies
are all copying what's working.
And as a creator,
you must do the same thing.
I once did a video on metabolism
and someone said to me,
"It's apparent you've
watched Jeff Nippard's video on
metabolism." And I said, "Mate,
are you crazy?
Of course I watched Jeff Nippard's video
on metabolism.
He has the most viewed video on it on the
internet.
I'd be doing you a disservice, brother,
if I didn't go watch the highest
viewed videos on metabolism before making
my video about metabolism." I
had to go take a few nuggets from him to
make mine good enough to be good enough
for you.
And you can't say I copied Jeff Nippard
because my video was hilarious,
and Jeff Nippard has never been hilarious.
So when it comes to copying, we
are seeking inspiration from things,
and that
is a good thing because
when you see someone doing better than you
or performing
better than you,
your mind can go in two directions.
You can resent them
or you can be inspired by them.
And if you are going to get quite close to
copying someone too far, you just credit
them and you say, "I learnt this from Ed.
I learnt this from Jeff." Hell,
you can even start a video by going, "I
watched this video
and it had such an impact on me,
I'm going to make the same
video so it can have an impact on you."
And as long as you're crediting where
you're getting information from, fine.
Fair game.
But even some of MrBeast's
and some of Ryan Trahan's biggest videos
have been
copied from smaller creators.
Originality does not exist.
And actually, the people that
are trying to be original
and trying to do something
for the first time, bum.
If you want to grow it,
if you want to grow your brand,
your business, your socials,
maybe one in five videos do your own
thing.
Carte blanche, as they call it.
But for the other four out of five,
you want to
make sure that you
are staying in line with what's working
because those channels
that are bigger than you,
more successful than you,
that make more money than you,
when you go and look at what lead magnet
they use or how they do the introductions
to their videos, you
are actually jumping
and skipping past years of failed
attempts and being frustrated
and things that don't work.
Renzo Gracie would've tried so many
submissions that never worked.
John Danaher comes along
and in 5 years learnt what Renzo learnt in
years. Then Gordon Ryan can come along
and learn in one year what it took John
five
years to learn.
It's the exact same on YouTube,
which means that the more novice
you are as a creator coming through,
and the younger you are, you little
whippersnappers. Even
if you look at the fitness industry,
people that arrive at
training now have so much evidence
and randomized control
trials about hypertrophy, about fat loss.
As time goes on,
you get to skip years of frustration
and not knowing and get
straight to it. So as an early creator,
you have got so much information in front
of you on what works
and what doesn't work
that life's never been easier.
So 100% go out there
and look to steal good ideas and
make them better. Actually, this
is another one of Ed's.
He calls it skyscrapering.
At some point,
someone has to build the highest
skyscraper in a city.
Then another developer comes along
and goes,
"Let's make one a little bit higher."
The other person makes it a little bit
higher.
Now,
the person that made the first video can
go, "Oh, that's annoying." Or they
can make another big one,
and at the same time a third party's come
along and said,
"Seeing them two big towers,
let's make one bigger than that."
And then eventually
everyone's just trying to out-skyscraper
each other, and what are you left with?
A beautiful skyline.
I used to have a big problem with people
copying and ripping
off each other's content. But
if you do it classily and gentlemanly,
it can be a
weapon for growth.
Another thing I copied from Ed
was his ability to just point to
another video that he'd made on YouTube
before and getting you to click that, so
I'm going to do that now. And this
is what YouTube recommends you should
watch.
And the best thing
is you could steal this video
and make it even better than the
bloody way I made it. So good luck